<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on 0xstark</title><link>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on 0xstark</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:14:28 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Making sense of Trust Experience (TX)</title><link>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/trustexperience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:14:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/trustexperience/</guid><description>The distinctive value of blockchains is that they can be reliable.
Blockchains can be made consistently resistant to manipulation, censorship, or capture. Their design can make them reliably transparent and accessible. Blockchains do not merely have those properties temporarily - we value them because we have good reason to believe this characteristic hardness will persist.
This deceptively simple property has enabled higher-order features. By combining this reliability with a programmable computing environment, blockchains have enabled digital property (like cryptocurrencies, tokens, and NFTs), complex global financial systems, and other use-cases where we care about reliability, like identity systems and social networks.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Smart (legal?) Contracts</title><link>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/legalcontracts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:17:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/legalcontracts/</guid><description>Introduction to Smart (legal?) Contracts
Josh Stark
0x4aa9
September 17th, 2021
👋 Note: Originally published in April 2016 on Coindesk and Medium.
Over the last year, the concept of a “smart contract” has received renewed attention in both the technology industry and in legal and business circles. Recent advancements in a field known as “blockchain technology” have led some to believe that smart contracts could soon offer alternatives to traditional commercial and financial agreements, with dire results for the legal and financial sectors.</description></item><item><title>Ethereum's distinctive property is hardness</title><link>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/hardness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/hardness/</guid><description>Hardness is the capability to make the future more certain.
Ethereum offers us hardness. We can give Ethereum code and receive a very strong guarantee that it will run any time we call on it. We can give Ethereum data and know with certainty it will still be available in the future, unaltered and uncorrupted.
These simple building blocks give rise to more complex forms of coordination. Money. Contracts. Governance. Identity.</description></item><item><title>What was Bitcoin's total transaction volume in 2021?</title><link>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/bitcointxvolume/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/bitcointxvolume/</guid><description>By Josh Stark &amp;amp; Bruno Lulinski
In the Year in Ethereum 2021, we published a chart comparing the total transaction volume of the Ethereum and Bitcoin blockchains. Last year, Ethereum transferred approximately $11.6 trillion (ETH and ERC-20s), and Bitcoin transferred approximately $4.6 trillion (BTC and USDT).
After publishing, we saw a graph from Galaxy Digital claiming that in 2021 Bitcoin had settled $12.41 trillion USD:
Ark Invest also posted a chart with similar figures, showing Bitcoin settled $13.</description></item><item><title>Atoms, Institutions, Blockchains</title><link>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/aib/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/aib/</guid><description>0. What do a book, a radio broadcast, and the human voice all have in common?
Today the answer is easy: they all contain information.
But if you asked someone the same question 100 years ago, they would struggle. They would not have easily identified that these different things all share an abstract property like “information”.
The modern idea of information is a recent invention. It was not until the 1940s that new communications technologies pushed people working on the cutting edge to articulate that there was something universal underlying sound, electromagnetic waves, symbols on paper, and much more.</description></item><item><title>The Year in Ethereum 2021</title><link>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/yie2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/yie2021/</guid><description>By Josh Stark &amp;amp; Evan Van Ness
Ethereum is the foundation for a digital civilization.
It is hardened, secure, and reliable. It is the bedrock necessary to support the digital cities being built on top of it.
Those cities are growing fast. Because Ethereum is open to everyone, many different users have found reasons to build on it:
Markets use it as financial infrastructure Artists use it to give permanence to their work Assets use it as a settlement layer Communities use it to govern shared resources This year Ethereum applications exploded into public consciousness.</description></item><item><title>The Year in Ethereum 2020</title><link>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/yie2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/yie2020/</guid><description>👋 Note: Originally published on Jan 20, 2021 on Medium.
Ethereum is the digital frontier.
Because it is open and programmable, Ethereum offers a vast uncharted expanse filled with opportunity.
Over the last few years, this frontier has attracted its first major settlements. The freewheeling bazaar of decentralized finance (“DeFi”) has grown into a sector that is beginning to compete with Silicon Valley. This year, a second ecosystem began to put down roots: the creator economy of cryptoart, music, and media.</description></item><item><title>The Year in Ethereum 2019</title><link>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/yie2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jjmstark.github.io/website/posts/yie2019/</guid><description>👋 Note: Originally published on Jan 22, 2020 on Medium.
Ethereum began as a blank canvas.
Ethereum is an open, permissionless blockchain that developers can use to create any kind of application they want.
This year, the early strokes laid down on that canvas began to form into a coherent picture.
You don’t have to squint so much to see the direction Ethereum is going. Protocols and applications built on Ethereum are beginning to find product-market fit, quickly building communities of thousands of paying users.</description></item></channel></rss>